# **EVERITT GILL**

Asheville, NC

Phone: 706-818-4445 | Email: eg.everittgill@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/everitt-gill-dev/

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/EverittGill">https://github.com/EverittGill</a>

Portfolio: <a href="https://everittgill.github.io/Everitt-Gill-React-Portfolio/">https://everittgill.github.io/Everitt-Gill-React-Portfolio/</a>

#### SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer graduating in the top of the class from Georgia Institute of Technology's Web Development Bootcamp. Developed Market Dash, an Al-powered marketing optimization tool focused on simplifying the user experience. Former Real Estate business owner with over \$6 million in sales within a 12-month period. Strong background in managing professional relationships, data-driven decision-making, and finance.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Technical Languages: JavaScript ES6+, SQL, HTML5, CSS3

Applications: MongoDB, MySQL, GitHub, Express, React, Node, Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap, Tailwind

CSS, Ethereum, ProLink

## **PROJECTS**

Market Dash https://github.com/EverittGill/Market-Dash https://tinyurl.com/market-dash

- Highly responsive AI powered marketing tool to allow farmers market vendors to promote their products and shoppers to preview the market with the help of my custom AI assistant
- Developed the AI assistant and back end. I was the first student ever in my bootcamp to develop a chatbot that connects to our back end data.
- Used OpenAl API, graphQL, MongoDB, React, Tailwind CSS, Apollo Server and Client, NodeJS, NPM, client/server architecture,

The Vault | https://github.com/EverittGill/The\_Vault | https://tinyurl.com/the-vault-password-saver

- Encrypted password saver allowing users to create an account and store passwords for websites or offline use
- I worked in all areas of this application from the HTML/CSS to the back end encryption.
- Used NPM, NodeJS, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Model View Controller architecture

## **Soccer Betting Game**

https://github.com/EverittGill/Soccer-Betting-Mini-Game https://tinyurl.com/soccer-betting-game

- A rather funny front end application to bet on soccer games
- I wrote almost all of the HTML and CSS for this as well as some of the JavaScript
- Used Bing maps API, sports API, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, DayJS, Bulma

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Redfin June 2021 - July 2022 Real Estate Associate Agent Asheville NC

- Used proprietary software to advance my ability to guide clients through the home buying and selling process with less stress and greater success
- Developed and maintained professional relationships with clients

## Everitt Gill Real Estate August 2019 - May 2021 Realtor/Owner Jacksonville Beach, FL

- Performed all jobs associated with being a Realtor and sold \$6,000,000 over a 12 month period
- Focused on lead generation, client follow up, and education daily
- Provided the highest level of service at all times to my clients and other agents
- Developed and implemented successful marketing campaigns over multiple mediums

# Pattison English January 2019 - July 2019 English Teacher Harbin, China

- Taught English as a second language in Harbin, China
- Worked with special needs students to offer specialized support

# **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp Certificate: Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars.js, and ReactJS. Final grade 96.6/100

Georgia College and State University: Attended in 2015 for business, did not graduate